I'm back in the project and now I want to deploy this application.
Projeye geri dndm ve imdi bu uygulamay datmak istiyorum.
So this is the project as we left it,
Yani bu, braktmz proje,
I didn't change anything.
ben hibir eyi deitirmedim.
Now the first thing is the base path,
imdi ilk ey temel yol,
we can see this in the
bunu uygulamada
app.js file,
grebiliriz. Js
excuse me, in the index.js file where we have the browser router, there we could set the basename property
dosyas, zr dilerim, dizinde. js dosyas, tarayc ynlendiriciye sahip, orada basename zelliini
but I plan on serving my app from mydomain.com/nothing
ayarlayabiliriz fakat uygulamanz mydomain'den sunmay planlyorum. com / yok bu yzden bunu
so I don't need to set this. Now
ayarlamanza gerek yok. imdi sradaki ey,
the next thing is that I need to ensure that the server always returns to index.html file,
sunucunun her zaman dizine dndnden emin olmamz gerektiidir. html dosyas, tm statik konaklar genellikle
that is something all static hosts typically allow you to configure and if you're not using a static
yaplandrmanza izin verir ve eer statik bir ana bilgisayar kullanmyorsanz ama nodejs
host but you are using your nodejs server, you just need to write code, you need to set up a catch all
sunucunuzu kullanyorsunuz, sadece kod yazmanz gerekiyor, tm rotay yakalamanz ve geri dnmeniz gerekiyor
route and return index.html
indeks. html ve
and the same logic of course applies for any other server side language.
ayn mantk elbette dier herhangi bir sunucu taraf dili iin de geerlidir.
So for us here, the next step is to build the project and this is run with the npm command,
Yani bizim iin burada, bir sonraki adm projeyi ina etmektir
npm run build. This will now build our project, similar to npm start but now it will also spit out a folder
ve bu npm komutuyla altrlr, npm run build. Bu, imdi npm balangcna benzer bir ekilde projemizi ina edecek, ancak
and not just store the result in memory and that folder will contain our optimized production build.
imdi bir klasr dar karacak ve sadece sonucu bellekte depolamayacak ve bu klasr, optimize edilmi retim yapmz ierecektir.
So there, we get this new build folder now in the project folder and if we have a look at this, we see
Bu yzden, bu yeni derleme klasrn imdi proje klasrne alyoruz ve buna bir gz
our single page which also is optimized to consume as little space as possible.
attmzda, mmkn olduunca az alan tketmek iin optimize edilmi tek sayfamz gryoruz.
You'll see that some script imports were added there, like to this main js file and that is what we
Bu ana js dosyasnda olduu gibi, baz betik aktarmlarnn eklendiini greceksiniz
can find in the static folder,
ve statik klasrde bulabildiimiz
there we got our media files, images like the burger logo and the javascript files for our different
ey, medya dosyalarmz, burger logosu gibi resimler ve farkl paralarmz iin javascript dosyalar
chunks for lazy loading and the main js file.
var. tembel ykleme ve ana js dosyas iin.
We also got source maps here,
Burada da kaynak haritalarmz var,
now you don't need to deploy these though, these are purely optional,
imdi bunlar datmanza gerek yok, bunlar tamamen istee bal,
you can focus on the javascript files but you can also and that is what I'll do deploy
javascript dosyalarna odaklanabiliyorsunuz ama ayn zamanda tm yap klasrnn ieriini
the content of the whole build folder and that's important.
datacam ey de budur. ve bu nemli.
The content of the build folder, ship that content, all the files there and the static folder to your static
Oluturma klasrnn ierii, ierii, tm dosyalar ve statik dizini statik sunucunuza
host.
gnderir.
So now let's deploy this.
imdi imdi konualm.
We'll do this in the next lecture.
Bunu bir sonraki derste yapacaz.